libsyn.com 2019-06-25

# Privacy Policy | liberated syndication (libsyn)

This policy statement reviews privacy practices associated with the website Libsyn.com, software products and online services of Liberated Syndication (“Libsyn”).  Libsyn may make periodic updates to its policy without notice; Privacy Policy updates will be published on the Libsyn website and/or user portal.

 **Personal and Corporate Information**  
Libsyn provides rich media broadcast promotion and advertising services and distributes media and software products for those services individuals, small businesses, major enterprise customers and ISPs.  Libsyn understands its customers’ need to protect personal information, billing information, and user account information. Use of Libsyn Services requires that Libsyn gather, track and use personal information for effective operation and support.  It is the nature of our software to gather and study specific information about customers, computer systems, network usage and IP addresses, user profiles and e-mail addresses, and the use of media programs in order to generate and study usage patterns, usage history, compliance with account policies respecting e-mail or software usage, advertising and promotional usage, and so forth.

Libsyn reserves all rights in the statistical and aggregate data that it generates from Libsyn Services, and the right to use that information to provide data services and support Libsyn Services to its customers.

 **Requested Information**  
We request and use personal and corporate information when you create an account, authorize end users, request or operate Libsyn Services, create and publish data reports, provide advocacy support with ISPs or corporate sites regarding your broadcast usage, or correspond with us. For example, if you request technical support online or via telephone, we will ask you for information necessary to authenticate you as a customer or end user, and to provide the requested support, such as your name, address and information about your computer hardware, software and the nature of the problem you are experiencing.

In most cases, customers will be asked to provide personal and corporate account information specific to each Libsyn Product & Service.  This information will, in most cases, be required for Libsyn to provide the service in a secure environment to you.  This may include your name, address, business information, e-mail, US Mail, telephone, facsimile, IP address(es), network domain(s), subscription, credit card or other billing information, and other information necessary to provide effective services, maintenance and support to your account and your end users.  In general, Libsyn will store and use such personal and corporate account information to provide you with Libsyn Services.

Libsyn may record support calls, create tracking tickets, log files, or other records of your support or user requests, for purposes of supporting you as a customer and/or providing Libsyn Services to you.  In representing you or Libsyn on public resources, such as discussion groups, technical searches, Libsyn will maintain anonymity for its customers.

Some Libsyn Services may create data files containing your personal and customer information; that information is subject to your control and dissemination is dependent upon your own security and privacy practices.  We advise you to inform your end users of such policies and practices.

Libsyn also maintains active license records embedded within Libsyn Services.  Libsyn will perform compliance audits on its network systems using your personal and corporate information, system usage, billing and account information, in order to maintain a registered subscriber base and to maintain usage records, and to prepare customer invoices and license renewals.

We may also maintain such recordings, logs or other records to track usage of the Libsyn Services by end users and to track the status of maintenance and support dialogues with end users and customers, to improve our services to customers.

Providing requested personal and corporate information is completely voluntary.  While individuals are under no obligation to provide such information to Libsyn, our customers may not get the full benefit of our products, services and support without providing such information.  In some cases, you may not be able to access user accounts online or operate Libsyn Services if you withhold such information.

 **Policy Changes**  
In the event there is a major change to our privacy practices, Libsyn will in most cases provide advance notice to its users via postings on the Libsyn website and/or user portal, or via e-mail.

If the change involves the use of your personally identifiable information, the notice will contain instructions on how you can opt-out of such use, or modify your personal information to suit the intended use.

If the change involves changes to your assigned user account information, personal and corporate information, billing information, and/or related web and e-mail addresses, the notice will direct you to an administrative console to review and/or edit the information associated with your user account or provide you with contact information so that you can make the requested changes in a secure manner.

 **How We Use the Information We Gather and Track**

In many cases, you may decide whether authorize any operation that requests personal information. If you do not wish to provide the requested information, however, you may not be able to use the pertinent Libsyn Services.   This includes operating services online, as well as Libsyn support and maintenance.

Libsyn will use personal and corporate information as follows:

  1. To provide you with information about the Libsyn Services,
  2. To provide you with informative newsletters, e-mails, and future product ideas or improvements;
  3. To provide you with end user support and account maintenance information;
  4. To assist Libsyn in creating better products and services for its customers;
  5. To provide information to and advocate for Libsyn customers with ISPs and corporate network administrators;
  6. To provide information about aggregate usage and trends on topics relating to account management; and,
  7. To provide you with access to information or otherwise engage in activities, such as product testing or evaluation for Libsyn Services.

 **With Whom We May Share Your Information**  
From time to time, unless we have stated otherwise, we may provide certain information to ISPs and corporate network administrators in order to effectively provide Libsyn Services to you. For example, in providing support services for our customers, Libsyn may need to share information about your services, privacy policy and account informatoin with support personnel at ISPs and Libsyn Service Partners.

In addition, Libsyn may from time to time retain the services of outside contractors or third parties to provide and/or host online services for its customers. Such parties may provide online maintenance and technical support or perform other services for Libsyn customers. We require that these contractors keep the personal information of customers secure and confidential. We also require that these parties use your personal and account information only your behalf and/or to provide direct support for Libsyn Services.  If you prefer that we not provide your information to such parties, you may let us know by using one of the methods described in this policy.

 **Response to Legal Disclosures**  
Please be advised that in certain instances, it may be necessary for Libsyn to disclose personal and corporate information about its customers at the request of government officials or agencies, by subpoena or legal proceeding, or otherwise as required by contract or other legal obligations.   This could include a court proceeding, foreign or domestic, that requires us to disclose such information.  Libsyn may make such disclosures without prior notice to its customers, and without seeking prior advice and counsel of its customers.

 **Limiting the Use of Personal Information**

You may ‘opt-out’ of receiving additional information from Libsyn or having Libsyn provide your personal information to our Service Partners. Libsyn may offer these choices at the time it requests your personal or corporate information and/or at the time you access Libsyn Services.  Libsyn may request that you verify personal or corporate, account or billing information from time to time as you use Libsyn Services.

If you would like to change your user preferences and account information, you may contact Libsyn and/or access the administrative pages for your account on the applicable Libsyn Website.  Methods for doing so appear at the end of this policy statement.

If you do not wish to continue receiving promotional communications from Libsyn, such as e-mail or online newsletters, you can opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to the unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or changing your communication preferences on the administrative pages for your account.

Status information on account, account usage, billing, billing practices, user profiles and changes thereto, system status, and so on, may also be sent by Libsyn using your personal and corporate information.  You can opt-out of receiving such communications changing your communication preferences in the administrative console associate with your Libsyn Services.

Modifications to your personal and corporate information, and restricting its use by Libsyn Product & Services may, however, curtail the level of service or communications thereon provided to you by Libsyn.

We make a sincere effort to respond to your requests to update or correct your personal information. If you believe that Libsyn does not have your current personal information, please contact us to update it.

 **Security and Quality of Personal Information**  
We have taken security measures to protect your personal information, including technical and procedural steps to protect your data from publication, misuse, unauthorized access or dissemination, loss, alteration or destruction.

Since Libsyn is a global company, we provide company information worldwide to service partners and ISPs. The personal information that you have provided to us may be transferred to other Libsyn servers around the world. Also, in certain countries, outside contractors might undertake the collection, transferring, storage and processing of your information.

 **Web Site Traffi** c  
We may track specific information about your use of Libsyn Services, including domain names, IP addresses, email addresses and browser types.

Such information may be correlated with your personal information by Libsyn in order to provide you with Libsyn Services, to provide support to you and your end users, and to consult with and advocate for you at ISPs and whitelisting services.

 **Service Partners**  
Through links on the Libsyn Services, customers may be asked to provide sensitive personal and/or corporate information to Service Partners of Libsyn.  In general, personal information provided to Libsyn will be protected by such Service Partners by requirements at least as strict as Libsyn’s own privacy policies. However, Libsyn is not responsible for the privacy practices of nor compliance thereto by our Service Partners. We encourage you to read their privacy statements, as they may differ from ours in some particulars, and in some cases Service Partners may require your assent prior to giving support and/or services to you.

 **Cookies**  
Libsyn may use cookies from time to time. A cookie is a small amount of data stored on the hard drive of the individual’s computer that allows us to identify the individual with his or her corresponding data that resides in our databases. You may read more about cookies at http://cookiecentral.com/  Libsyn may use cookies to personalize your experience on our online services or portal pages, or to track en user usage of Libsyn services for customers. If you do not want Libsyn to deploy cookies in your browser, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a Website tries to put a cookie in your browser software. Rejecting cookies will affect your ability to use of some of the products and/or services at the Libsyn Services.

Libsyn may also use cookies to track your visit to our Websites. While our Web servers may automatically log your IP address, such basic Internet traffic statistics will not be tied back to other personal information.

 **Other Privacy Management Practices To Consider**  
Please remember that information you submit in a discussion group, blog or other forum will be deemed published, public information and is therefore no longer confidential. The communication of personal and account information in such venues means that that information can be collected and used by others, and you should assess that risk before doing so.  This includes your disclosure of information concerning your account profile, personal data, or other data obtained by use of the Libsyn Services.

Libsyn cannot maintain the security of your account, nor ensure the accuracy of your results using Libsyn Services, nor provide remediation concerning your relationships with ISPs and network administrators, if you make such public disclosures.

 **Contact Information**  
If you have any questions or comments, or if you would like to change your communication preferences, please contact us.

This policy last updated March 2013
